Gregory Amaefule

Owerri Municipal, Imo, Nigeria

amaefulegregory@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/gregory-amaefule-547a7b225

Summary

My name is Gregory Amaefule and I'm a 3rd-year undergraduate in Electronic and Computer Engineering at the Federal University of Technology, Owerri. I'm a highly motivated self-starter who is passionate about Cloud technologies, Software engineering, and real-life problem-solving. I am heavily invested in my self-development, gradually transitioning from an intermediate-level programmer to an advanced-level programmer who is able to apply tools at his disposal to real-life problem-solving through several programs and Bootcamp I am currently enrolled in (some of which include the Linux Foundation Cloud Engineer Bootcamp). I am eager for experience(both technical and non-technical) in the Cloud and Software engineering space. I love sharing ideas, building projects, contributing to projects, making new connections, and building inclusive communities. I have also been directly involved in several campaigns aimed at creating a stronger coding community at FUTO (the GDSC & IEEE communities are some of them). I am always on the lookout for opportunities to grow and help others grow such as this one.

My skills include:

JavaScript, Python, Kotlin, C++, Linux Sys. Administration, Cisco Networking, OOP, Data Structures and Algorithms, Databases, React, TailWind, CSS, SASS, DOM, Git & Github, HTML, Strategy, Problem-solving, Communication & Presentation, Leadership, Writing.

Experience



IEEE Power & Energy Society

Jan 2022 - Present (9 months +)

Leading the providers of scientific and engineering information on electric power and energy for the betterment of society on the Students Branch Chapter level.

Linux System Administrator Trainee

The Linux Foundation

Jun 2022 - Present (4 months +)

Learning how to administer, configure and upgrade Linux systems running one of the three major Linux distribution families (Red Hat, SUSE, Debian/Ubuntu). Also learning all the tools and concepts I need to efficiently build and manage a production Linux infrastructure.

Data Structures & Algorithm Bootcamp

Microsoft ADC & NACOS

May 2022 - Jul 2022 (3 months)

Mastered the fundamentals of the design and analysis of algorithms. This Bootcamp covered the modeling of computational problems, as well as common algorithms, algorithmic paradigms, and data

structures used to solve these problems. It introduces basic performance measures and analysis techniques for these problems.

Education



Federal University of Technology Owerri Nigeria

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Electrical and Electronic Engineering Sep 2018 - Sep 2024

Relevant Coursework: Computer Programming, Algorithms and Data Structures, Computer Architecture, Engineering Statistics, Numerical Methods, Engineering Algebra.



Cisco Networking Academy

Cisco Certified Network Associate

Jul 2022 - Dec 2022

CCNA training covers networking fundamentals, IP services, Switching, Routing, Wireless Essentials, Enterprise Networking, Security fundamentals, automation, and programmability. Designed for agility and versatility, CCNA validates that you have the skills required to manage and optimize today's most advanced networks.

Frontend Masters

Bootcamp, Frontend Engineering

Jul 2022 - Dec 2022

Advancing my Skills with In-Depth, Modern Front-End Engineering Courses.

Learning JavaScript, CSS, SCSS, Website Accessibility, Animations, Figma for Developers, REACT, Databases, Linux, Dev Tools, Web UX design, Building Progressive Web Apps, AWS for Frontend Engineers, Firebase, Web Components, Advanced Asynchronous JavaScript, Git In-depth, Content Strategy, The Hard Parts of Object Oriented JavaScript, Datastructures and Algorithm

Claret Academy Secondary School Owerri

Managed the Science laboratory in teachers' absence.

Coordinated study groups for WEAC and various inter-school competitions

Organized and supervised other students during various school activities like assemblies, sports, labor, Holy Mass etc.

Licenses & Certifications



Responsive Web Design - freeCodeCamp

Skills

Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) • Writing • Databases • Algorithms • Data Structures • C++ • JavaScript • Python (Programming Language) • React.js • Linux

Honors & Awards

MTNF Scholarship 2021 - MTN Nigeria

Aug 2021

Science and Technology Merit Scholarship awarded to sophomore university students in public institutions in Nigeria for outstanding academic performance

Linux Foundation Training (LiFT) scholarship - The Linux Foundation Jun 2022

Awarded each year to 500 promising individuals from around the world with professional training and certification on top open source technologies at no cost to help them start or advance their careers.